ocsb.ca 2016-12-01

# Privacy Information Management (PIM) - Ottawa Catholic School Board

##  Privacy Information Management (PIM) 

The Ottawa Catholic School Board is rising to the twin challenges of addressing the growing demand for access to information and the heightened expectations surrounding the security and protection of personal information. All Board employees are responsible for the protection of personal, confidential, and sensitive information entrusted to them. The Board is committed to the protection of privacy and complies with all applicable provisions in the Education Act, the Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (MFIPPA), the Personal Health Information Protection Act (PHIPA), and any other applicable legislation. Our Board's Privacy & Information Management Committee (PIM) works to raise awareness on matters of public trust and confidence with respect to privacy. We understand that it is vital that this privacy culture be embedded into our daily practices to support the needs and expectations of parents, students and staff with respect to information security and the protection of personal information. Contact our PIM Committee Chair, Tim Slack, Principal at St. George School. Phone 613-728-8291 or email [Tim.Slack@ocsb.ca](mailto:Tim.Slack@ocsb.ca). The OCSB follows provincial legislation to protect the privacy of an individual's personal information. This Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (MFIPPA) also provides a process for the public to access specific information from the OCSB. Sometimes, a formal freedom of information (FOI) request is made by an individual to the OCSB. You can make a freedom of information request by following a prescribed set of steps. You will need to complete some documentation, and pay an application fee. 

It is the practice of the Ottawa Catholic School Board to collect, use, retain and disclose personal information in the course of meeting its statutory duties and responsibilities. The management of personal information collected by the OCSB for these purposes is in accordance with the provisions of the Education Act, the Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (MFIPPA), and the Personal Health Information Protection Act (PHIPA).

Personal information will only be used for the purpose for which it is intended. The Board shall ensure that personal information is secured and protected from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, and inadvertent destruction by adhering to safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the information. Upon request, the OCSB shall allow an individual to access his/her personal information and will be given access to that information in accordance with privacy legislation, subject to any mandatory or discretionary exceptions.
